Jarrett Dougherty

jarrettdougherty@gmail.com | Philadelphia, PA

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jarrett-dougherty-4506381a2/

GitHub: https://github.com/JarrettD5309 Website: https://jarrettd5309.github.io

Career Summary

Full-stack web developer with specialization in social media and project management. Skills in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, Express.js, MySQL, MongoDB, React.js, and responsive web design. Extensive experience in team management, project coordination, and creative collaboration via 15+ years in the international music industry.

Technical Skills

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, Express.js, MySQL, MongoDB, React.js, RESTful APIs, AJAX, React Native, Git, Adobe Photoshop, Figma

Education

University of Pennsylvania Rutgers University (Cook College)

Coding BootCamp

Bachelor of Science

Philadelphia, PA

New Brunswick, NJ

2020 2007

Full-Stack Web Development (A+ avg)

Plant Science (Highest Honors)

Applications Built

Sckedio (ongoing)

- <u>Deployed:</u> <u>https://sckedio.herokuapp.com/</u>
- <u>Code: https://github.com/JarrettD5309/sckedio</u>
- Role: Front-End Developer/Team Leader
- <u>Description:</u> An online marketplace platform that connects designers, manufacturers, and buyers.
- Language/Tools Used: Node, Express, React, MySQL, Axios, Material UI, JWT.

Jarrett Dougherty

jarrettdougherty@gmail.com | Philadelphia, PA

TennisMatch

- <u>Deployed: https://tennis-match-react.herokuapp.com/</u>
- Code: https://github.com/greg-a/tennis-match-react
- Role: Developer (user login authentication, server routes, UI/UX, MySQL queries)
- <u>Description:</u> A full stack scheduling application, created by a team, that helps players to schedule tennis matches with other players.
- <u>Language/Tools Used:</u> Node, Express, React, MySQL, Express-Sessions, Crypto, Sequelize, FullCalendar, Material UI, Moment, Socket.io, React Router.

MoodConnect Website

- Deployed: https://www.moodconnect.com/
- <u>Code: https://github.com/MoodConnect/mood-connect</u>
- Role: Developer/Regular Maintenance
- <u>Description:</u> Primary website for startup app company.
- <u>Language/Tools Used:</u> HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Photoshop, Figma, Formspree, Mailchimp, AWS.

Experience

Sckedio, Inc

Team Leader of Front-End React Team/Intern 11/2020 – present

- Building front-end experience for startup using React
- Promoted to team leader of three-person front-end team of interns
- Successful communication between founders, back-end developer, and frontend team via Slack and Zoom
- Completed milestones ahead of schedule

MoodConnect LLC

Web Developer; Contract 12/2020 – 01/2021

- Successfully designed, built, and deployed a new website through regular communication with company founder
- Created, updated, and maintained company visual assets via Adobe Photoshop and Figma
- Accomplished migrations to AWS Amplify and Route 53 with no loss of service

Jarrett Dougherty

jarrettdougherty@gmail.com | Philadelphia, PA

Screaming Females LLC

Owner/Manager/Performer/Songwriter 08/2005 – present

- Musician and songwriter in an internationally known musical act
- Managed and designed social media and web presence
- Conceptualized and implemented numerous international product launches and campaigns
- Managed and facilitated communication across an international team
- Created, monitored, and maintained multiyear budgets
- Organized and administered contracts, customs paperwork, and licensing agreements